Guide to the Semans family papers, 1878-2008 and undated RL.01167
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- James H. and Mary D.B.T. Semans Family Papers, 1925-1991
  The James H. and Mary D.B.T. Semans Family Papers span the years 1925 to 1991. The bulk of the papers date after 1950, except for the Pictures Series which dates from the 1880s to 1990. Included in the papers are genealogical materials; correspondence; financial papers; legal papers; subject files pertaining to the many academic institutions and philanthropic, artistic, and social organizations in which the Semanses are involved; writings and speeches; scrapbooks; photographs; and other materials such as audio tapes, awards and certificates, calendars, clippings, motion films, and phonograph records. The papers also document the commitment of the Semans and Trent families to use their personal and financial resources to support artistic endeavors, academic institutions, and research in social welfare and medical programs, particularly in North Carolina.
  Papers dating from 1925 to 1953 focus on Mary Duke Biddle Trent Semans; her personal and family life including travel, school life, musical pursuits, her marriage to Josiah Charles Trent and their family life and activities; and her relationship with Elizabeth L. Gotham, the family's personal assistant and childcare provider. Mary D.B.T. Semans's philanthropic, political, and social activities are also illustrated. The development of Mary and Josiah C. Trent's collection of rare book materials and their donations of these to the academic and medical libraries of Duke University are described, as well as their relationships (and later Dr. Semans's) with book dealers Henry and Ida W. Schuman.
  James H. Semans's papers merge with those of Mary Semans beginning in 1953, the year in which the two were introduced and subsequently married. After their marriage, materials reflecting the Semanses' joint and individual activities are interspersed throughout the series.
  The Correspondence and Subject Files Series form two of the largest and most important components of the papers. There is much overlap of topics between the two series. The papers demonstrate the continuing interest of Duke family members in the welfare of Duke University and the institutions served by The Duke Endowment. Mary Semans's positions with the Duke University Board of Trustees and numerous committees, the Woman's College, and with The Duke Endowment are documented, especially in the Subject Files Series. Correspondents for Duke University include university presidents, officers and staff, especially Douglas M. Knight, Terry Sanford, Keith Brodie, Thomas L. Perkins, Benjamin E. Powell, and Joel L. Fleishman. Medical Center correspondents include Barnes Woodhall, Wilburt C. Davison, Lenox D. Baker, and William G. Anlyan. The Duke Endowment correspondents include Marshall I. Pickens and Robert McCormack. However, since many of these individuals operated within several organizational spheres, their correspondence may be scattered.
  James and Mary Semans's involvement with Duke University's Art and Music departments and other programs and events are described in the Correspondence and Subject Files Series. Mary Semans participated in the development and expansion of the academic and medical libraries. James Semans was instrumental in the expansion of the medical library in the 1950s. Their trusteeship in the Mary Duke Biddle Foundation and its contributions to Duke University and the arts outside of the university are prominently represented. Other educators and civic leaders who corresponded with the Semanses include William C. Friday, George Watts Carr, Jr., and Dan K. Moore.
  The North Carolina School of the Arts was heavily supported by the Semanses, particularly by Dr. Semans who is a school founder. The school, including its summer sessions in Siena, Italy, is documented primarily in the Subject Files Series, but references will be found also in the Correspondence and Miscellaneous Series, and additional photographs are in the Pictures Series. The correspondence illustrates the close personal and professional relationships of the Semanses with school staff and students. Prominent people represented in the North Carolina School of the Arts materials include Vittorio Giannini, Robert C. Suderburg, Samuel M. Stone, and Giorgio Ciompi.
  The Correspondence and Subject Files Series document the Semanses' work in the arts and their memberships in many arts organizations, including the Advisory Board of the Institute of Fine Arts at New York University and the Concert Opera Board of New York City, and James Semans's extensive connections stemming from the North Carolina School of the Arts. Numerous artists, writers, musicians, dancers and art supporters have close ties with the Semanses. Correspondents for these areas include John Ehle, Iain Hamilton, Nancy Hanks, Agnes De Mille, and Archie K. Davis.
  The Semanses sponsor music scholarships and prizes, artistic programs and concerts, and have commissioned art and musical works at Duke University, the North Carolina School of the Arts, and elsewhere. A number of endowments, funds, scholarships, and foundations have been started by the Semanses in support of the arts, social and medical research, and other academic endeavors. They also sponsor a collection of art for Duke University in honor of Dr. Semans's parents.
  The Correspondence and Subject Files Series also reflect the extensive involvement of Dr. and Mrs. Semans in medical and vocational rehabilitation in local, state, and national organizations in the late 1950s through the 1960s. There is significant correspondence from Mary Switzer and Howard Rusk for this area. Three major subject files of these materials are Duke University Medical Center, the National Paraplegia Foundation, and Vocational Rehabilitation.
  The Correspondence Series also contains information on family, personal, social, and business activities and relationships. There is correspondence from Duke, Biddle, and Semans family members. The close relationships between the Semanses and members of the Trent family of Oklahoma and elsewhere after Josiah C. Trent's death are reflected in the correspondence. The correspondence also reflects many of the Semanses' close personal relationships with people in North Carolina, New York, Pennsylvania, Washington, D.C., Italy, and Greece.
  The Trent and Semans children, Mary Duke Trent Jones, Sally Elizabeth Trent Harris, Rebecca Gray Trent Kirkland, Barbara Biddle Trent Kimbrell, Jenny L. Semans Koortbojian, James D.B.T. Semans, and Beth Gotham Semans are also described throughout the Correspondence, Pictures, and Miscellaneous Series. This includes information on their academic and professional activities as well as their personal and adult family lives.
  Copies of many of the speeches given by the Semanses at the ceremonies in which they received awards and at other public occasions are in the Writings and Speeches Series. Files, including correspondence and other related materials, created by Dr. Semans and his assistants for the publication of an autobiography titled Coming of Age are also in the Writings and Speeches Series. Some of the correspondence in the autobiographical files does not relate to the publication of the book but is background information compiled by Dr. Semans.
  The Scrapbooks Series consists of three scrapbooks compiled by Mary D.B.T. Semans during the 1930s. They illustrate her travels across the U.S., her student years at Duke University, and her courtship with Josiah C. Trent.
  People represented in the Pictures Series include the Angier family of North Carolina, the Biddle family of Philadelphia, the Duke family, the Trent family (related through Josiah Charles Trent) of Oklahoma and elsewhere, and the Semans family of Pennsylvania and elsewhere. For most of these individuals there are candid photographs as well as formal portraits. Family-oriented subjects include children's birthday parties (1920s), family group Christmas portraits that were also reproduced on Christmas cards (1941-1988), weddings, travel in the U.S. and Europe (1950s-1980s), and leisure in Atlantic City, N.J. (ca. 1915-1920s), southern resorts, and at home. This series provides an opportunity for an examination of affluent society in the 1920s and 1930s. A significant number of the pictures were made by professional photographers, and many were reproduced on the newspaper society pages. There are extensive photographs taken in Palm Beach, Fla., showing people engaged in recreational activities and pictures of homes and social clubs.
  Many larger papers and photographs are in the Oversize Materials series found at the end of the Semans Family papers.
  Additional information on Dr. Josiah Trent, Mary D.B.T. Semans's first husband, are found in his papers, also held in the Rubenstein Library.
  - Genealogical Papers Series
    - Biddle family, 1950-1987,undated (Box 13)
    - Drexel family, 1970, 1975, 1983 (Box 13)
    - Duke family, 1958-1988,undated (Box 13)
    - Roney family, 1941,undated, 4 folders (Box 13)
    - James H. Semans family, 1956-1990 (Box 13)
    - Mary D.B.T. Semans family, 1972-1980s (Box 13)
    - Josiah C. Trent family, 1928-1983,undated (Box 13)
  - Correspondence Series
    - 1927-1949, Apr., 16 folders (Box 14)
    - 1949, May-1954, 16 folders (Box 15)
    - 1955-1959,undated, 15 folders (Box 16)
    - 1960, May-1961, 12 folders (Box 17)
    - 1962, Jan.-1964, Dec., 11 folders (Box 18)
    - 1965, Jan.-1966, Dec., 9 folders (Box 19)
    - 1967, Jan.-Dec., 8 folders (Box 20)
    - 1968, 11 folders (Box 21)
    - 1969, 12 folders (Box 22)
    - 1970, 13 folders (Box 23)
    - 1971, 13 folders (Box 24)
    - 1972, 13 folders (Box 25)
    - 1973, 13 folders (Box 26)
    - 1975, 8 folders (Box 27)
    - 1976, 12 folders (Box 28)
    - 1977-1978, Oct., 14 folders (Box 29)
    - 1978, Nov.-1979, Dec.and undated, 15 folders (Box 30)
    - 1980, 12 folders (Box 31)
    - 1981, 13 folders (Box 32)
    - 1982, 11 folders (Box 33)
    - 1983, 9 folders (Box 34)
    - 1984, 11 folders (Box 35)
    - 1985, 11 folders (Box 36)
    - 1986, 12 folders (Box 37)
    - 1987, 12 folders (Box 38)
    - 1988, Jan.-1989, May, 17 folders (Box 39)
    - 1989, June-1991, May, 13 folders (Box 40)
    - undated, 8 folders (Box 41)
    - Condolences: Josiah Charles Trent (Box 42)
      - 1948, Dec. 10-30,undated, 6 folders (Box 42)
      - Telegrams, 1948, Dec. (Box 42)
      - Funeral, 1948, Dec. (Box 42)
    - Condolences: (Box 43)
      - Mary Duke Biddle
        - 1960, June 15-Aug.,undated (Box 43)
        - Telegrams, 1960, June (Box 43)
        - Funeral, 1960, June 16 (Box 43)
      - Anthony J. Drexel Biddle (Ambassador to Spain)
        - Appointment, Service, 1961, Mar.-Sept. (Box 43)
        - Illness and death, 1961, Oct.-Dec., 2 folders (Box 43)
        - Telegrams, 1961, Nov. (Box 43)
  - Financial Papers Series
    - General, 1948-1990 (Box 44)
    - Cash receipts/disbursement statements, 1946-1990, 3 folders (Box 44)
    - Trial balance, 1964, 1976-1982 (Box 44)
    - Property: (1009 Fifth Avenue)
      - 1960, 1967-1990, 5 folders (Box 44)
      - Restoration Contract, 1982 (Box 44)
      - History and Architecture of 82nd St. from Fifth Ave. to Madison Ave., 1975 (Box 44)
  - Legal Papers Series
    - Duke University, Trent/Semans Gifts to, 1949-1965 (Box 45)
    - Estates: (Box 45)
      - Biddle, Mary Duke, 1960-1967, 3 folders (Box 45)
      - Duke, Sarah P., 1937-1984 (Box 45)
      - Gotham, Elizabeth L., 1961-1987 (Box 45)
      - Trent, Josiah C., 1949-1950, 1967 (Box 45)
      - Non-family, 1967-1986 (Box 45)
    - Property: Pinecrest, 1936-1980,undated (Box 45)
    - Trusts:
      - Children, 1964-1984,undated (Box 45)
      - Duke, Doris, 1924-1925 (Box 45)
      - Semans, James H., 1964-1986 (Box 45)
    - Wills:
      - Semans, James H., 1954, 1959-1960 (Box 45)
    - Wills: Semans, Mary D.B.T. (Box 46)
      - 1940-1987, 4 folders (Box 46)
      - Appraisals, 1979-1985,undated (Box 46)
      - Codicils, inserts, 1977-1986 (Box 46)
      - Index, undated (Box 46)
  - Subject Files Series
    - American Dance Festival, 1980-1987 (Box 47)
    - Arts (general), 1966-1990, 4 folders (Box 47)
    - Arts Advocates of North Carolina, 1984-1990 (Box 47)
    - British/American Festival, 1982-1984 (Box 47)
    - Bull Durham Movie Premiere, 1988, Apr. (Box 47)
    - Community Chest, 1949-1952,undated, 2 folders (Box 47)
    - The Cooperative School for Pregnant School Girls, 1970-1971 (Box 47)
    - Cornish Institute, 1984 (Box 47)
    - Cosmos Club, 1956-1966 (Box 47)
    - The Duke Endowment, 1963-1986, 13 folders (Box 48)
    - The Duke Endowment: (Box 49)
      - 1987-1990,undated, 3 folders (Box 49)
      - Angier B. Duke Memorial, Inc., 1973-1989 (Box 49)
      - B.N. Duke Leadership Fund, 1985-1988, 1990 (Box 49)
      - The Doris Duke Trust, 1968, 1974, 1976, 1979-1990, 3 folders (Box 49)
      - Educational Affairs (self-study), 1976 (Box 49)
      - Hospital and Child Care Division, 1960, 1980-1989 (Box 49)
      - Job descriptions, undated (Box 49)
      - The Nanaline H. Duke Fund, 1982, 1985 (Box 49)
      - Salary study, 1981 (Box 49)
    - Duke Family Association, 1989 (Box 50)
    - Duke Homestead, 1968-1982 (Box 50)
    - Duke University, 1958-1979,undated, 12 folders (Box 50)
    - Duke University, 1980-1990,undated, 13 folders (Box 51)
    - Duke University: (Box 52)
      - Art Department, 1967-1988, 5 folders (Box 52)
      - Art Museum, 1965-1989,undated, 2 folders (Box 52)
      - Chapel, 1961-1983,undated (Box 52)
      - Board of Visitors, 1971-1972 (Box 52)
      - Drama Program, 1980-1990 (Box 52)
      - Duke Media Center/N.C. Film Institute, 1974 (Box 52)
      - Duke-Semans Fine Arts Foundation, 1981-1988 (Box 52)
      - East Campus Parlors, 1979-1986 (Box 52)
      - Gothic Bookshop, 1986 (Box 52)
      - Harriet C. Carter Lectureship Committee, 1968-1969 (Box 52)
      - Institute of Art, 1980-1989, 2 folders (Box 52)
    - Duke University: (Box 53)
      - Library, ca. 1943, 1960-1985 (Box 53)
      - Mary Lou Williams Memorial, 1980-1981 (Box 53)
      - Music Department, 1972-1989,undated, 6 folders (Box 53)
      - Translation Service, 1976-1985,undated (Box 53)
      - University Planning Committee/Fine Arts Subcommittee, 1971-1973 (Box 53)
      - Vigil: Martin Luther King, 1968, Apr. 8 (Box 53)
      - White Duchy:
        - Organization correspondence, 1947-1948 (Box 53)
        - Alumnae (Reorganization)/Questionaire, By-laws, ballots, 1947 (Box 53)
        - The Lucky Number, 1947, 1949 (Box 53)
      - Woman's College:
        - Board of Visitors, 1964-1971 (Box 53)
        - Dean of Women, Search Committee, 1968 (Box 53)
        - Memorial rooms, 1972 (Box 53)
    - Duke University Medical Center (Box 54)
      - 1955-1990, 9 folders (Box 54)
      - Davison Symposium, 1961 (Box 54)
      - Library Committee, 1958-1962,undated (Box 54)
      - Trent Collection in the History of Medicine, ca. 1940-1966 (Box 54)
    - Durham, N.C.: (Box 55)
      - 1955-1985, 2 folders (Box 55)
      - Mayor's Committee on Human Relations, 1958-1959 (Box 55)
      - Race Relations, 1950s-1960s (Box 55)
    - Durham Arts Council, 1983-1990, 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Durham Homes, Inc., 1968-1981 (Box 55)
    - Durham Homes, Inc., Financial Statements, 1969-1978 (Box 55)
    - Durham Social Planning Council, 1955-1958 (Box 55)
    - Elizabeth City State University Foundation, 1968-1975 (Box 55)
    - Executive Mansion Fine Arts Committee, 1965-1990,undated, 10 folders (Box 56)
    - Josiah Charles Trent Fund, 1974-1980,undated (Box 56)
    - Josiah Charles Trent Memorial Foundation, Inc., 1977-1988 (Box 56)
    - Kittrell College, 1968,undated (Box 57)
    - Linden Court [Irvington-on-the-Hudson], Tarrytown, N.Y. (renovations), undated (Box 57)
    - Louisburg College, 1955-1985,undated (Box 57)
    - Mary Duke Biddle Foundation, 1963-1982, 11 folders (Box 57)
    - Mary Duke Biddle Foundation: (Box 58)
      - 1983-1990,undated (Box 58)
      - Annual Report, 1970-1985 (Box 58)
    - Mary D.B.T. Semans Foundation, 1982-1983 (Box 58)
    - National Institute of Musical Theater, 1984-1985 (Box 58)
    - National Paraplegia Foundation, 1955-1970, 3 folders (Box 58)
    - North Carolina Civil Liberties Union, 1965-1969 (Box 58)
    - North Carolina Museum of Art: (Box 59)
      - 1961-1989,undated, 6 folders (Box 59)
      - Director (selection), 1969-1970 (Box 59)
      - Mary Duke Biddle Gallery for the Blind, 1968-1987
        - Site selection:
          - 1972-1975 (Box 59)
          - Analysis, 1972 (Box 59)
    - North Carolina School of the Arts, 1961-1970, 8 folders (Box 60)
    - North Carolina School of the Arts, 1971-1977, 10 folders (Box 61)
    - North Carolina School of the Arts, 1978-1985, 13 folders (Box 62)
    - North Carolina School of the Arts: (Box 63)
      - 1986-1990,undated, 7 folders (Box 63)
      - Board of Trustees:
        - Minutes, 1964-1989 (Box 63)
        - Notes, undated (Box 63)
      - Board of Visitors, 1984-1985 (Box 63)
    - North Carolina School of the Arts: (Box 64)
      - Hipp, William E., III: Bust of James Semans, 1980-1986 (Box 64)
      - International Music Program, 1971-1991, 7 folders (Box 64)
      - Search Committee, 1967-1990, 4 folders (Box 64)
    - North Carolina School of the Arts: (Box 65)
      - Semans Art Fund, 1977-1990 (Box 65)
      - Siena:
        - 1967-1977 (Box 65)
        - Histories, 1974-1976 (Box 65)
        - Clippings, 1964-1987 (Box 65)
    - North Carolina School of the Arts Twenty-fifth Anniversary, 1991 (Box 66)
    - North Carolina School of the Arts Foundation, Inc., 1964-1984, 4 folders (Box 66)
    - North Carolina School of the Arts, Pictures: (Box 67)
      - 1975-1986,undated, 3 folders (Box 67)
      - International Music Program (IMP), 1983, 1991 (Box 67)
      - Italy
        - Concerts, 1967-1968 (Box 67)
        - Audience with the Pope, 1968 (Box 67)
        - Siena, 1967-1968, 2 folders (Box 67)
    - North Carolina Symphony, 1969-1983, 2 folders (Box 68)
    - Southern Railway Company, 1963-1964 (Box 68)
    - Vocational Rehabilitation, 1955-1986, 7 folders (Box 68)
    - Volunteer Services Bureau of Durham, 1971 (Box 68)
    - Warren Wilson College, 1971-1985 (Box 68)
    - Women in Action for the Prevention of Violence and Its Causes, Inc., 1968-1981 (Box 68)
  - Writings and Speeches Series
    - Mary D.B.T. Semans: (Box 69)
      - Children's Writings/Drawings, 1929,undated (Box 69)
      - Diary, 1930 (Box 69)
      - 1947-1977, 9 folders (Box 69)
    - Mary D.B.T. Semans, 1978-1991, 7 folders (Box 70)
    - Mary D.B.T. Semans, undated, 13 folders (Box 71)
    - Mary D.B.T. Semans, undated, 13 folders (Box 72)
    - Mary D.B. T. Semans: (Box 73)
      - undated, 4 folders (Box 73)
      - Fragments, 9 folders (Box 73)
    - James H. Semans: (Box 74)
      - 1955-1977, 5 folders (Box 74)
      - European trip, 1958 (Box 74)
      - Greece, 1963 (Box 74)
      - Norway, 1960 (Box 74)
    - James H. Semans: (Box 75)
      - 1978-1990, 6 folders (Box 75)
      - undated, 4 folders (Box 75)
    - James H. Semans, Autobiography, 1985: (Box 76)
      - Background information, 1957-1982 (Box 76)
      - Correspondence (re: publication), 1984-1986 (Box 76)
      - Curriculum Vitae information, 1985 (Box 76)
      - Expenses, 1985 (Box 76)
      - Family emblem, 1985 (Box 76)
      - Family tree, notes, chart, 1985 (Box 76)
      - Langston Hughes quote source, 1985 (Box 76)
      - Mailing lists, 1985 (Box 76)
      - "New" scrapbook subtitles, 1985 (Box 76)
      - Photographs, subtitles, 1985 (Box 76)
      - Clippings, 1985 (Box 76)
      - Preface, 1985 (Box 76)
      - Acknowledgements, 1985 (Box 76)
      - Table of contents, 1985 (Box 76)
      - Bibliography, 1985 (Box 76)
      - Index, 1985 (Box 76)
      - Interviews, 1981-1983, 3 folders (Box 76)
    - James H. Semans, Autobiography, 1985: (Box 77)
      - Transcripts, 1984, Jan.-July, 4 folders (Box 77)
      - Manuscripts, 1984, June-Nov., 2 folders (Box 77)
      - Corrections, 1984, Nov., 3 folders (Box 77)
    - James H. Semans, Autobiography, 1985: (Box 78)
      - Manuscript, 1985, Mar.-Apr., 2 folders (Box 78)
      - Corrections, 1985, June-1986, 4 folders (Box 78)
      - Blueline copy, 1985 (Box 78)
      - Published copy, 1985 (Box 78)
      - Reminiscences, 1990- (Box 78)
  - Scrapbook Series
    - Scrapbooks: (Box 79)
      - 1934-1935 (photocopy), 2 folders (Box 79)
      - ca. 1936 (Box 79)
      - ca. 1937, 3 folders (Box 79)
    - Scrapbook: (Box 80)
      - 1934-1935 (original, moldy; see container 79 for photocopy) (Box 80)
  - Pictures Series
    - Albums: (Box 81)
      - ca. 1914-1920 (Box 81)
      - ca. 1920s, 7 folders (Box 81)
    - Albums: (Box 82)
      - ca. 1912 (Box 82)
      - ca. 1921-1922 (Box 82)
    - Upright Boxes
      General note
      N.B. There are two alphabetical sequences of loose pictures. Size considerations created the need to store pictures in both flat and upright boxes. Therefore the first alphabetical sequence refers to pictures in upright boxes, the second to pictures in flat boxes, e.g., pictures of Anthony J. Drexel Biddle are in boxes 83 and 90.
      - Angier, Malbourn Addison (engraving), undated (Box 83)
      - Biddle, Anthony J. Drexel:
        - ca. mid-1910s-1940s (Box 83)
        - ca. 1917,World War I (Box 83)
        - ca. 1920s (snapshots) (Box 83)
        - ca. 1920s-1930s, Palm Beach, Fla. (Box 83)
        - and children, ca. 1920s-1930s (Box 83)
      - Biddle, Anthony J. Drexel and Biddle, Mary Duke, ca. mid-1910s-1930s (Box 83)
      - Biddle, Livingston, ca. 1915, undated (Box 83)
      - Biddle, Margaret Atkinson Loughborough and children, 1960-1987 (Box 83)
      - Biddle, Mary Duke:
        - ca. 1890s-1950s, 8 folders (Box 83)
        - 1920s-1930s, with children (Box 83)
        - ca. 1940s-1960s, with Semans, Mary D.B.T. and grandchildren (Box 83)
        - 1949,Dedication Mary Duke Biddle Room (Box 83)
      - Biddle, Nicholas Benjamin Duke, ca. 1925-1952,undated, 5 folders (Box 83)
      - Duke, Angier Biddle and Duke, Anthony Drexel, ca. 1920s, undated (Box 84)
      - Duke, Angier Buchanan:
        - ca. 1890s-1920 (Box 84)
        - 1910s-1923 (with family and friends) (Box 84)
        - 1915,Wedding (Box 84)
        - ca. 1920-1925, with sons (Box 84)
      - Duke, Benjamin Newton:
        - ca. 1890s, undated (Box 84)
        - ca. 1890s, engraving, portraits, 2 folders (Box 84)
        - ca. 1890s, 1920s, with family (Box 84)
        - undated, sculpture (Box 84)
      - Duke, Benjamin Newton and Duke, James Buchanan, ca. early 1900s (Box 84)
      - Duke, Benjamin Newton and Duke, Sarah Pearson Angier:
        - ca. 1910-1920,with others (Box 84)
        - ca. 1920-1925,with family (Box 84)
        - ca. 1925, Atlantic City (Box 84)
      - Duke, Cordelia Drexel Biddle, ca. 1915 (Box 84)
      - Duke, James Buchanan, ca. 1875-1925,undated (Box 84)
      - Duke, Sarah Pearson Angier, ca. 1930s (Box 84)
      - Duke, Washington:
        - ca. 1880s-1890s (portrait) (Box 84)
        - ca. 1890s, with grandchildren (Box 84)
        - 1904, Erwin Mills Associates (Box 84)
      - Duke family, undated, unidentified (Box 84)
      - Harris, Sally Elizabeth Trent and family, 1942-1986, 2 folders (Box 85)
      - Jones, Mary Duke Trent and family, 1941-1980s, 4 folders (Box 85)
      - Kimbrell, Barbara Biddle Trent, ca. 1950s-1980s (Box 85)
      - Kirkland, Rebecca Gray Trent, 1943-1983 (Box 85)
      - Koortbojian, Jenny Lillian Semans, 1950s-1979 (Box 85)
      - Semans, Elizabeth Gotham, ca. 1966-1984, 1979-1981, 2 folders
        - Bull Durham Movie Premiere, 1988 (Box 85)
      - Semans, James Duke Biddle Trent, 1957-1970s, 2 folders (Box 85)